Last week, the entire Silicon Valley
startup ecosystem was brought to its
knees by one man, the Sohon Perek. If
you haven't heard this name yet, imagine
this. You are a Silicon Valley startup
founder. You've got VC money burning a
hole in your pocket for some lame AI
business idea. But the problem is that
you need humanpowered engineers, good
ones, and fast. If you happen to be one
of these startup founders, there's a
good chance you interviewed Sohon Pere.
Hell, he might even be working at your
startup right now because he's mastered
the art of crushing the computer science
interview that tons of companies have
given this guy job offers, but rather
than limit himself to just one, he
decided to work at all of them. He's a
developer who turned remote work into a
multi-threaded concurrent career and
broke the internet in the process. In
today's video, we'll take a look at the
current state of the job market in tech
and find out how Sohon Perk was able to
stay 10x over employed. It is July 7th,
2025, and you're watching the code
report. The programming job market has
been stuck in feast or famine mode for
several years now. If you're looking to
land your first job, entry-level
positions are harder than ever to come
by, and layoffs are still consistently
happening at big tech. Although not
technically fang, Microsoft just laid
off 9,000 souls a few days ago. But FANG
feels like a very outdated acronym in
2025. Going forward, I'll either use
Mango or Gay Man. Just let me know which
one you prefer in the comments. The job
market's tough to break into right now,
but if you have legit skills in machine
learning and data science, you might
find yourself getting nine figure offers
from Zuckerbucks to poach you from scam
Altman. Initially, Altman said that
nobody took up Zuckerborg on his offer,
but the new super intelligence roster at
Meta would beg to differ, and OpenAI
recruiters are seething on Twitter.
Unfortunately though, AngularJS
developers like me are not getting any
nine-figure offers. The job market might
be broken, but if you know how to
exploit it, you can still make millions
of dollars. So Perek is a talented
software developer who focused all of
his energy on mastering the interview
process to impress people who make the
hiring decisions. He would entice them
with a flattering email about how
awesome their company is, then had the
actual lead code skills to crush the
interview. Once hired, he would halfass
just enough work to stay employed as
long as possible while simultaneously
doing the same thing at four or five
other companies. If he was making 200k
per job, he could easily clear a million
dollars per year doing this. And even if
he underperforms at a job, it could
still take weeks or even months to fire
him. Initially, people speculated that
he was doing arbitrage by hiring a team
of interns to make all of this possible.
But he claims that he was working 120
hours per week and all of his code was
organic and handcrafted by Soham
himself. He's been running this grip
since 2022 and didn't even rely on AI
slop. He only got caught because the
founder of Playground AI dropped this
bombshell tweet that the guy was taking
advantage of them. It quickly went viral
because dozens of other startups
realized that Sohom was working for them
as well. He of course was quickly fired,
but he became something of a folk hero
in the tech world. And it's truly a
badge of honor to have hired Sohom or to
at least have interviewed him. If he
never reached out for an interview, it's
likely because your company sucks. But
he's not the only guy doing this. There
are many Sohs out there. The
overemployed subreddit has 400,000
members with all sorts of people
bragging about how they hold multiple
remote jobs. Ultimately though, Soh
received a lot of hate for his actions
online and even said he's not proud of
what he did. But the story has a happy
ending. He entered into an exclusive
relationship with Darwin AI and has a
golden opportunity to start his own
technical interview prep company. But
you have 80,000 hours in your career. 40
hours a week, 50 weeks a year for 40
years. That's a lot of time to make a
positive impact on the world. And 80,000
hours, the sponsor of today's video, can
help you do that. If you're young,
you've probably heard advice like follow
your passion, do what you love, and take
the initiative. But these cliches are
not based on evidence or data. Unlike
the work of 80,000 Hours, which is a
nonprofit that for the last 10 years has
been researching the question of how do
you find a fulfilling career that does
good, too. Their website, which is
entirely free, has tons of collected
research on high impact careers along
with job boards, podcasts, and a lot
more. It's an incredible resource for
anyone looking to start a high impact
career or make a switch mid-career. Join
the newsletter today to get a free copy
of their in-depth career guide sent to
your inbox. And remember, it's totally
free because it's a nonprofit and could
be the catalyst that changes your
direction in life. This has been the
Code Report. Thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next